# HEENA SINGH

#### Kolkata. West Bengal

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Curious, skilled, and fun-loving content writer with 4+ years of experience. Adept in writing buzz-worthy feature contents in a variety of industries, including technology, design, and finance. Aspire to create an impact in content curation that captures readers' attention and drives conversions.

#### **EDUCATION**

Sister Nivedita University

Bsc Honours in Psychology - CGPA-8.5

Kolkata, India

Oct 2021 - July 2024

Little Star High School

Higher Secondary - Percentage - 81

May 2019 - May 2020

Kolkata, India

#### WORK EXPERIENCES

Fandom Wire June 2024 - Present

Freelance Entertainment Journalist

- Researched and wrote high-traffic articles on trending entertainment topics, including movies, TV shows, and celebrity news.
- Utilized SEO best practices to enhance content visibility, increasing reader engagement and website traffic.
- Contributed to the editorial strategy by identifying and covering timely, relevant, and engaging entertainment stories.
- · Worked closely with editors and a team of writers to meet tight deadlines while maintaining high content quality.

## Harns Technologies Pvt .Ltd

Mar 2023 - Present

Freelance content writer

Remote

- Created well-researched and in-depth content blogs on veterinary medicine and animal care.
- Produced content for their software solution, adhering to a strict brief of headlines, quick facts, updates, and reviews.
- Created and established informational articles on high-tech and specialized topics.
- Generated 1,000 backlinks by writing over 34 articles about the veterinary space.

# Beeonlinedigital

Jan 2023 - Feb 2024

Freelance content writer

Remote-Kolkata, India

- Wrote 250+ SEO-friendly short-form and long-form content on a variety of topics, including business, healthcare, and promotional content.
- Brainstormed innovative solutions for content briefs, analyzing industry trends to drive more sales.
- Established content strategy and editorial plans with the team leader for upcoming projects, increasing organic website traffic by 18%
- Held meetings with clients, solving their problems with in-house content and suggesting solutions to formulate better marketing strategies.

# Nilsen Report

Dec 2020 - Feb 2024

Web content writer

Remote-Kolkata, India

- Wrote more than 2800 articles and blogs to date for their entertainment website and social media channels.
- Adhered to style guidelines and drived maximum audience traffic to content.
- Performed research, embedded links, presenting succinct and clear information, and communicating effectively with clients.
- Employed exceptional editing skills to generate professional, error-free copy.

73Buzz July 2023 - Jan 2024

### Freelance content writer

Remote-Kolkata, India

- Created and implemented 500+ engaging content pieces on sports celebrities, providing an insight into their net worth, careers, and personal life.
- Developed dynamic infographics to engage the audience, reach customers, and attract 8k+ visitors to the
- Organized material to research and complete writing tasks.
- Reduced plagiarism by 75% by editing copies for spelling errors, and style; fact-checked content of 15 writers, improving their work.

Apprify Feb 2023 - Dec 2023 Blogger Remote-Kolkata, India

- Created and published more than 60 engaging blog posts, promoting their founder and software solutions business on leading media platforms.
- Wrote a full-fledged thesis report about the company's founder on how he struggled to start the business and his growth story.
- Created infographics using Canva based on management instructions for blog posts, shooting up the traffic.
- Worked closely with the digital marketing team to optimize new and existing content, increasing readership by 34%.

## NewYork Daily Gazette

Dec 2021 - Sep 2023

Content writer and editor

Remote-Kolkata, India

- Researched and wrote SEO-friendly blog posts, web content, and articles on upcoming movies and television shows.
- Authored 1000+ fun and creative entertainment articles, which enhanced traffic by 18-25\% per month.
- Proofread 1500+ content and pointed out grammatical errors and other punctuation mistakes.

Oziva Mar 2021 - May 2023

Freelance writer

Remote-Kolkata, India

- Wrote over 43 blogs on their health supplements and protein powders.
- Derived sales conversion on their 'collagen builder' product by writing in-depth content.
- Assisted in writing content on women's health and weight loss that served a significant purpose.
- Maintained a knowledge base of Oziva's Bioactive range, including four separate product ranges.

The Page Talk Jan 2020 - Dec 2020 Remote-Kolkata, India

- Jr. Content Writer
  - Published educational blog content that attracted 8000+ monthly visitor
  - Optimished old website content with up to date SEO guidelines and increased trafftc by 15%
  - Maintained Content trackers and created monthly reports for management

#### **SKILLS**

**Technical:** Google Docs, Wordpress, Microsoft Office, Access, Excel, Outlook, PowerPoint and Word. Creative: Content writing, Creative writing, Editing and proofreading, Social media management, Content creation

Miscellaneous Skills: Time management, Problem solving, Effective communication, Team Management

# CERTIFICATIONS/ACHIEVEMENTS

- The Ultimate SEO Training 2023 + SEO For Wordpress Websites-UDEMY
- Basic to Advanced Content Writing 2023 UDEMY
- How To Write SEO Blog Posts UDEMY
- Secured 1st Rank in Inter-College Debate Competition
- Secured 2nd Rank in Creative Writing Competition